<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: thesis | YL's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://YunlongNie.github.io/tags/thesis/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://YunlongNie.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-23T12:56:01-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://YunlongNie.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[joha]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Latex Tips when doing Thesis]]></title>
    <link href="http://YunlongNie.github.io/blog/2013/08/23/latex-tips-when-doing-thesis/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-23T12:02:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://YunlongNie.github.io/blog/2013/08/23/latex-tips-when-doing-thesis</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just finish my thesis recently and it is time now to summary some the techniques that I feel quite handy.</p>

<h1>Template</h1>

<p>The template can be downloaded from this <a href="" title="http://www.phys.washington.edu/users/mforbes/projects/ubcthesis/">website</a>. In fact, all the need is the following files:
<code>
genthesis.cls
sample.bib
ubcthesis.cls
ubcthesis.dtx
ubcthesis.ins
ubcthesis.tex
</code></p>

<h1>Bibliography</h1>

<p>I use the package called <strong>natbib</strong> to control the style of Biblography. <strong>natbib</strong> is a latex packages. Please refer to this <a href="http://merkel.zoneo.net/Latex/natbib.php">web page</a>.</p>

<h2>Step 1 make a bib file.</h2>

<p>For example, my bib file is called <code>mybib.bib</code>, in which all the citation information is stored. Each term looks like this, which you can download easily from <strong>Google Scholar</strong>.
<code>
@article{iwai1996boostrap,
  title={The boostrap theory of money: A search-theoretic foundation of monetary economics},
  author={Iwai, Katsuhito},
  journal={Structural Change and Economic Dynamics},
  volume={7},
  number={4},
  pages={451--477},
  year={1996},
  publisher={Elsevier}
}
</code></p>

<h2>Step 2 annouce the package in your latex file.</h2>

<p><code>
\usepackage[authoryear,round]{natbib}
</code></p>

<p>The <code>autheryear,round</code> are certain option. In this case, the reference will be displayed like <code>AutherName(1988)</code>. More optionns are available. Please refer to this <a href="http://merkel.zoneo.net/Latex/natbib.php">web page</a></p>

<h2>Step 3 cite in the article</h2>

<p><code>
\citet[iwai1996boostrap]
</code></p>

<h2>Step 4 creat reference section</h2>

<p>Put the folllowing code after last chapter and before the appendix
<code>
\bibliographystyle{plainnat}
\bibliography{mybib}
</code></p>

<h2>Step 5 complile</h2>

<p>complile the latex file in Latex twice. Then complile it with BibTex twice. Once again, complile it in Latex twice.</p>

<p>Bingo!</p>

<h1><code>\Input</code> command in latex</h1>

<p>Often, I recommmand to use input when you are writing a long article in latex so that you can put tex code in each chapter into seperate tex files. The main latex file for to generate the whole pdf is just a skeletion of your book or thesis. For me, it is always a pain in the ass to track a long tex files, say including 10,000 lines of code.</p>

<p>you can even use \input in your <code>input</code> files. But \include cannot be used in that way.</p>

<p>\input is super useful when you like to creat figures and tables. It allows reproducible work. See my older <a href="http://yunlongnie.github.io/blog/2013/07/19/r-my-own-function-to-generate-text-code-for-figure/">post</a> about how you generate a tex code for figure.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
